Profile Summary

- 1) Three years of experience in Software Development.
- 2) Currently working in Angular 4, TypeScript, JavaScript, NodeJS.
- 3) Excellent programming ability in Javascript.
- 4) Strong knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms.
- 5) Experience in Agile methodology.

Technical Skills

Languages	C, JavaScript, Java
Tools	Eclipse, GIT , CVS, VIM, GCC
Technologies and Frameworks	NodeJS, AngularJS, Angular 4, TypeScript,
	NW.js(<u>https://nwjs.io/</u>),Electronjs(<u>https://electronjs.org/</u>) Cordova
Others	Data Structures and Algorithms

Education

- MCA (2011-2014) from Jawaharlal Nehru University with CGPA 7.19/9.
- BCA (2007-2010) from Dr. BR Ambedkar University Agra, UP

Work Experience

Next Education India Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad, India
Engineer-Product December, 2016 – Present

TeachNext (Team Size 8)

About: TeachNext is the current only bread and butter of the company. Teach Next is a unique in-class learning solution for schools. It provides digital content aligned to the syllabuses of CBSE, ICSE, IGCSE, and 23 state boards in 8 languages including Hindi. Teach Next comes in 2 product variants for maximum flexibility.

a) Individual classroom solutions:

In this simple set up, it is possible to digitise individual classrooms. It combines the best of hardware, software, content and service that delivers new-age technology and and traditional classroom teaching.

b) Server- platform: school wide solutions:

In this platform the entire school is digitised at once. The Teach Next Application Server is installed on a server in a Central Coordination Center (CCC) at the school. Individual classrooms are then connected to the CCC via a local area network (LAN)

Responsibility:

- 1. Complete ownership of desktop version
- 2. Designing the application
- 3. Code optimization.
- 4. Mentoring team
- 5. Code reviews.
- 6. Encrypting and decrypting content images and videos and serving to end user.

Language and Technologies used: Angular 4, NodeJS, NW.js

Next Books (Desktop Application, Mobile App), Science Lab (Desktop Application, Mobile App), Next Mentor (Web Application, Mobile App) K-12 Education (Team Size 4)

About: Next Books, Science Lab, Next Mentor are three products based on single code base. Providing different functionalities as per the individual flags. Next Books comprises of Interactive activities, Digital form of the hard book for children created in HTML5 using in5 plugin. All three products had activation logic, covers books from Pre-Primary to class 12. Science Lab contained science experiments videos to help students build science experiments. Next Mentor comprises of suggestive, detailed daily teaching plan for the entire year with assessments, Question banks and more

Responsibility:

- 7. Complete ownership of desktop version and the Cordova Android Application.
- 8. Enabling activation mechanism.
- 9. Complete overhaul of the application design and functionality.
- 10. Code optimization.
- 11. Mentoring interns
- 12. Code reviews.
- 13. Encrypting and decrypting content images and videos and serving to end user.

Language and Technologies used: AngularJS, NodeJS, NW.js, Cordova, Android

Kony Labs India Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad, India
Software Engineer
July, 2015 – December 2016

Kony Visualizer Enterprise Edition / Starter Edition

About: The product is a mobile application development platform for building mobile, tablet, desktop, and kiosk applications. Kony Visualizer is one of several platform supports that developers can use to build mobile applications for consumers and enterprises. Kony Visualizer supports iOS, Google Android, HTML5, Windows and Blackberry.

Responsibility:

- 1. Handling properties window (PW) tab in the Kony Visualizer product. Where the PW window enlists the properties of the elements dropped in the single page Application.
- 2. Writing automation test cases using selenium in Java for end to end application testing.

Language and Technologies used: Java, Javascript, NodeJS

Achievement: Awarded Team Award for integrating Mobile Fabric(MBBAs services) and also for Best Tools team

Automation Framework for Visualizer end to end testing

About: The product has been built to automate the two products Visualizer Starter and Enterprise Edition to test the end to end scenarios.

Responsibility:

- 1. Creating and maintaining automation framework to automate the entire application using various tools namely: Selenium for UI automation, Squish for Eclipse automation and Sikuli for image comparison.
- 2. Code review for new features

Language and Technologies used: Java, Selenium, Squish(https://www.froglogic.com/squish/gui-testing/), Sikuli, Batch Scripting

3) Aricent, Gurgaon, India

Software Engineer

Jan, 2014 – Jun, 2015

IMS RCS Client (Internet Multimedia Services Rich Communication Suite)

About: IMS RCS Client (Internet Protocol Multimedia System Rich Communication Suite Client) "Core part of a chip embedded in mobile phone". It provides functionalities like voice call, video call, Sharing Geo-Location, Chat, file transfer etc.

Responsibilities: Responsible for handling 2 modules.

Capability Discovery: This modules enquires the capability of the module to

- 1) Social Presence Information e.g. Availability status, geo location, favorite link, etc.
- 2) Writing the software requirement specification (SRS)
- 3) Design the feature (HLD, LLD).
- 4) Development of the feature.
- 5) Developing test cases and testing features.

Language and Technologies used: C, LTE, SIP and SIMPLE protocol, Visual Studio 2013.

Achievement: Awarded WOW-Team Excellence Award for Quality delivery

IMS-AS-Lite (Internet Multimedia Services – Application Server)

About: This project provides the facility for the user to move from LTE to non LTE network even during the call is alerting, confirmed or in inactive state. This project is based on LTE technology using SIP protocol. **Responsibilities:** Responsible for handling 2 modules.

- 1) RM module (Resource Manager)
- 2) In a team of 4 members handling CSH (Call Session Handler) module
- 3) Design and development of the feature.
- 4) Developing test cases and testing features.
- 5) Bug fixing.

Language and Technologies used: C, LTE, SIP, Linux platform

IMS-Lite (Internet Multimedia Services)

About: Voice over Long Term Evolution (VOLTE) is a standard technology that supports voice calls to be made in an LTE network. It is developed using IMS technology. This is achieved using SIP technology.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Involved in a team of UEH (User Equipment Handler) module.
- 2. Involved in unit testing of various features.
- 3. Involved in System integration testing of various features.
- 4. AS (Application Server)registration, RTR (Registration Termination Request) and PPR (Push Profile request)

Language and Technologies used: C, LTE, SIP, Linux platform

Personal Information

D.O.B.	09th Sept, 1989
Languages Known	English, Hindi
Current/Permanent	G-707, BRC Infra Siv Hills, Puppalaguda, Hyderabad – 500089
Address	